Guide to the Elisabeth Lloyd Papers, 1954-2017 ASP.2016.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Conferences, 1989 - 2016; VII.
  - Programs, 1983 - 2016; 1.
    - Gruter Institute Conference on Biological Perspectives in Teaching Law and the Social Sciences - Squaw Valley, California, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Use of Biology in the Study of Law Teaching Seminar - Squaw Valley, California, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Science, Reason, and Rhetoric Conference - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - The Chapel Hill Colloquium in Philosophy - Chapel Hill, North Carolina, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Law, Biology, and Human Behavior Teaching Conference, Squaw Valley, California, June 1995 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Fifth International Congress of Systematic and Evolutionary Biology - Budapest, Hungary, 1996 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Iowa State ESA Symposium - Ames, Iowa, 1998 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - International Society for History, Philosophy, and Social Studies of Biology - Oaxaca, Mexico, 1999 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Bioquest Undergraduate Curriculum Development Summer Workshop, Beloit College - Beloit, Wisconsin, 1999 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Virgil C. Alrdrich Utah Philosophy Colloquium on Human Nature, University of Utah - Salt Lake City, Utah, 1999 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Kira Conference, Amherst College - Amherst, Massachusetts, 2000 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Philosophy of Science Association Symposium - Vancouver, British Columbia, 2000 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Central American Philosophical Association - Minneapolis, Minnesota, 2001 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - Groups, Multi-Level Selection, and Evolutionary Dynamics, Santa Fe Institute - Santa Fe, New Mexico, 2001 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Indiana University Arts and Sciences Chairs Retreat, 2003 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - International Society for History, Philosophy, and Social Studies of Biology - Vienna, Austria, 2003 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Ethics Committee Meeting at Yale University, 2005 (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - American Geophysical Union (AGU) Fall Meeting - San Francisco, California, 2009 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Models and Simulations 4 - Toronto, Canada, 2010 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Epistemology of Modeling and Simulation, University of Pittsburgh - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 2011 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - American Geophysical Union (AGU) Fall Meeting - San Francisco, California, 2011 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Feyerabend Conference, Humboldt-Universitaet zu Berlin - Berlin, Germany, 2012 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - American Philosophical Association Pacific Division Ninetieth Annual Meeting - San Francisco, California, 2016 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Materials, 1985 - 2015; 2.
    - American Philosophical Association - Eastern Division, Comments and Correspondence on Doren Recker's paper, 1985 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - National Women's Studies Association Conference, Session Proposal, Elisabeth Lloyd, Ruth Doell, Jane Braaten Perspectives on Feminist Empiricism, 1987 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Philosophy of Science Conference Notes, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Philosophy and Computational Neuroscience Symposium, APA Pacific Division, Lloyd's Comments on Chris Cherniak's Paper, 1993 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Pacific American Philosophical Society Schedule, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Fine Festschrift Conference at Ohio University, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - APA Interview Itinerary, 2003 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Human Biology Summer Institute, 2006 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - School of Philosophy/The Aristotelian Society Joint Session Conference, University of East Anglia, 2009 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - The Experimental Side of Modeling Workshop at San Francisco State University, 2010 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - ISH Random Notes, 2011 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Mismatch Workshop, 2011 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - American Philosophical Society Symposium Notes, 2012 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Evolutionary Mismatch and What To Do About It, EI/NESCENT Working Group, 2012 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Workshop on The Causal Factors of Robustness and Plasticity in Living Systems - Indiana University, 2014 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - The Epistemic Role of Manufactured Dissent in Climate Science MDCS, 2015 (Box 43, Folder 16)
- Professional Activities, 1992 - 2017; VIII.
  The items in this series document Lloyd's work in professional societies of which she was a member, in academic administration at her home institutions at both the departmental and the university committee level, and other activities that are part of the life of a professional academic, but not directly connected to her research and teaching.
  In addtion, there is a miscellaneous catagory containing items for less common actitiies such as magazine interviews, etc.
  - Departmental Administration, 1993 - 2013; 1.
    - Department Meeting, December 1993 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Departmental Meetings - UC Berkeley, 1993-1994 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Monday, July 2 1996 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Faculty Meeting, 1997 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Move Expenses, 1998 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Meeting, 2001 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - HPSC Faculty Meetings - Indiana University, 2002 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - HPSC Faculty Meetings - Indiana University, 2003 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Lab meeting - Indiana University, 2008 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - HPSC Faculty Meetings - Indiana University, 2009 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - External Review of Indiana University's Department of History and Philosophy of Science, 2009 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - HPSC Faculty Meetings - Indiana University, 2010 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - HPS stats reading group, 2013 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Graduate Program Revisions (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - University Administration, 1992 - 2013; 2.
    - Colloquia Committee, 1992 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Animal Care and Use Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Lloyd's promotion, 1997 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Lilly FLP Meeting, 2000 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - University of Illinois at Chicago Job Offer, 2000 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Contributing Author's Letter of Agreement - Violence Against Science: Rape and Evolution, 2001 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Lloyd's Planner, 2003 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Lloyd's Planner, 2004 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Richard Lewontin Paper Notes, April 2006 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Job Application to SUNY Stony Brook, 2013 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Dinner with Alan Code (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Template for Unsolicited Manuscript Reply but No Promise (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Template of Lloyd's Job Offer Rejection Letter (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Women in Science/Summers Debate Papers (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Professional Societies, 1988 - 2000; 3.
    - University of California Humanities Research Institute (UCHRI) Newsletter, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - UCHRI Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - UCHRI Miscellaneous Papers, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - UCHRI, January 4 1989 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - UCHRI, January 11 1989 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - UCHRI, January 18 1989 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - UCHRI, January 25 1989 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - UCHRI Notes, February 7 1989 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - UCHRI, February 8 1989 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - UCHRI, February 15 1989 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - UCHRI, February 22 1989 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - UCHRI, March 1 1989 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - UCHRI, March 8 1989 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - UCHRI, March 15 1989 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - UCHRI, December 1990 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - UCHRI, January 11 1991 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - UCHRI, January 25 1991 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - UCHRI, February 1 1991 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - UCHRI, February 8 1991 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - UCHRI, March 1 1991 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - UCHRI, March 8 1991 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - UCHRI Annotated Articles (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - UCHRI Glossary (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - UCHRI Miscellaneous Notes (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - UCHRI Philosophy and Biology (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - UCHRI Undated Transcripts (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Philosophy of Science Association, 1986 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Philosophy of Science Association, 1994-2000 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - International Society for the History, Philosophy, and Social Studies of Biology - Board of Directors Meeting, July 21, 1995 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Honorary Appointment to the Professional Women's Advisory Board by the American Biographical Institute, 2006 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Grants and Projects, 1985-2009; 1994-2009; 4.
    - NSF proprosal - "The Confirmation of Scientific Theories", 1985 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Research Grant Application on "Objectivity" and "Subjectivity", 1994 - 1995 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Humanities RA Proposal, 2005 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Climate Change Project, 2006-2007 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Fellowship Application, 2006-2007 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - National Science Foundation (NSF) Final Report for Climate Change Project, 2007 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - National Science Foundation (NSF) Final Report Notes, 2007-2008 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Fall Themester Lectures and Workshop Proposal, 2009 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - National Science Foundation (NSF) Proposal Notes (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Proposal for Regional Climate Models, 'Value Added', and 'Model Robustness' (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - 200 Word Project Summary (Publishable) (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989 - 2012; 5.
    - Appointment Request Forms (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - A Critic Takes on the Logic of Female Orgasm Article in the New York Times, 2005 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Dugatkin and Reeve Problems, 1994 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Email Records (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Floppy disks (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Folder with Miscellaneous Notes and Papers (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Hand Drawn Map of UC Berkeley (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Letter from Lloyd Regarding her Long Absence and Illness (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Contact Info for Others (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Notes and Scraps of Paper (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Objects Found (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Photographs (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Recommendation Letters for Colleagues, 2012 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Sabbatical info and souvenirs, 1989 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Taking the Naturalistic Turn: How Real Philosophy of Science is Done Conversations with philosophers, 1993 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - The Sciences in Human Perspectives for Princeton University Press Book Series (Box 50, Folder 16)
- Education, 1976 - 1984; IX.
  The materials of this series document Lloyd's post-secondary education. There are student papers, notes, and other writings from both her undergraduate and graduate education.
  - Undergraduate Education, 1977 - 1980; 1.
    - Binder-Philosophy 294, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Binder-Modern Political Thought, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Binder-Philosophy 300, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Binder-Philosophy 408, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Binder-Political Science 444, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Binder-History 419, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Binder-Political Science 440, 1979 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - History 419 Paper The Epistemology and Ethics of Johann Gotlieb Fichte, Fall 1979 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Folder-Philosophy 301, 1980 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Binder-Philosophy 493, 1980 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Binder-Miscellaneous Contents, 1980 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Lloyd's Honors Graduation Info CU Boulder, 1980 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Graduate Education, 1980-1984; 2.
    - Darwin Paper Notes, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Darwin Paper Drafts, 1983 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Garden State Graduate Fellowship, 1979-1983 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Job Search Notes and Listings, 1983-1984 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Misc. PhD Info, 1984 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Notes on An Introduction to the Study of Experimental Medicine and The Development of Modern Medicine (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Nosography: The Evolution of Clinincal Medicine in Modern Times and A History of Pathology (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Notes on the Works of Thomas Sydenham M. D. Volumes I and II (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Notes on The History of Biology, De Motu Cordis Et Sanguins, and Life Science in the Twentieth Century (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Unlabeled Blue Notebook (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Binder-Philosophy of Physics, 1981 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Binder-Philosophy 511, 1980 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Symons The Evolution of Human Sexuality, 1979 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Binder-Philosophy 312 Pt. 2, 1981 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Folder-Philosophy 511, 1980 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Folder-Philosophy 512, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Program in History and Philosophy of Science Info, Princeton University, 1980-1981 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Darwin Paper First Draft, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Empiricism Project-HPS 596, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - A Semantic Apporach to the Structure of Modern Evolutionary Theory, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - CS 106, June 1982-August 1982 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Philosophy 531 Jeffery Notes, October 1982 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Science in Human Affairs 290 Binder, Spring 1982 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Publication to Philosophy of Science-Notes, Drafts, Correspondence-The Nature of Darwin's Support for the Theory of Natural Selection, 1982-1983 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - American Association of University Women Educational Foundation Fellowship Application, 1983 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Arisotle's View of the Soul Paper by Lloyd, 1983 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Dissertation Notes-General, October 1983 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Dissertation Talk Notes (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Explanations in Biology talk, 1983 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Josephine De Karman Fellowship Application, 1983 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Lab Intros and Notes, 1983 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Department Placement-Info, 1983-1984 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Job Placement-Rejections, 1983-1984 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Lab Seminar Notes, 1983-1984 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Chapter One E. A. Lloyd Manuscript and Notes, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Report and Comments on Lloyd's Dissertation, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Job Placement Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - Aristotle Notes (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - Philosophy of Social Science (Box 56, Folder 18)
  - Biographical Material, 1983 - 2009; 3.
    - Elisabeth Lloyd CVs, 1999-2005 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Who's Who in America, 2000 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - IBC 2000 Outstanding Intellectuals of the 20th Century, 2001 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Alliance of Distinguished and Titled Professors - Indiana University, 2005 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Dictionary of International Biography - 32nd Edition - Lloyd Biography, 2005 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Great Women of the 21st Century, 2006 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 13: Elisabeth A. Lloyd, 2009 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Fragment of a bio written by Lloyd (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Guggenheim Career Summary (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - List of Elisabeth Lloyd's Publications, 1983-1996 (Box 57, Folder 10)